Phone Number: +351 914 578 268 E-mail: pmsg21@gmail.com

Location: Portugal (resident)

Languages: Spanish (Native) English (B2)

I'm a web developer with 6+ years of experience working with legal, insurance and security oriented companies, collaborating remotely with international teams. Although I have worked as a fullstack I'm currently dedicated to the frontend working with React, applying clean code and the S.O.L.I.D principles in each of my developments.

I have had the opportunity to work with different types of technologies and work methodologies (Scrum, Kanban), which has improved not only my knowledge but also how I interact with my colleagues and how I approach all challenges.

For my future I would like to continue developing on the frontend using libraries like React, learning new ways to structure code, and to use new technologies that will enrich the quality of my work and allow me to lead and support different teams and projects.

EDUCATION

Systems Engineer

Universidad Bicentenaria de Aragua (U.B.A) / 2011 - 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

— Software Engineer

Company: Webdox CLM / OChile (remote) / Jan 2022 - Aug 2023

- · Developed different sections of the application, in which I:
 - Added a new functionality that mitigated a significant security issue related to user password management.
 - Created a settings module that allows the enabling/disabling and permissions management of an important product feature.
 - Implemented a feature that restricts the types of documents the application allows, resulting in the product's security optimization.
- Developed several components in the design system, rigorously tested, which were subsequently integrated into the product, applying the necessary logic so that other developers could use them, which managed, for example, to prevent a considerable security risk regarding excessive resource usage
- · Worked on updating legacy components to eliminate technical debt and improve application performance.

React.js	Туре	Script (JavaScript	react-testing-li	brary	Jest	react-query
HTML5	CSS3	SASS	Storybook	Design System	Git		

— Semi-Senior Web Developer

Company: Initium Software / Venezuela / Mar 2020 - Dec 2021

- · Developed a functionality that generates quotes based on the information provided by the user of an insurance company.
- · Created an informative section about the insurance's functionality.
- · Worked on creating multiple REST services for CRUD operations of different records in the database.



— Software Developer

Company: Technology 4 Solutions / OUSA (remote) / Jan 2018 - Mar 2020

· Collaborated in the development of an application that allowed the GPS tracking of vehicles and users of a school route.

- · Implemented a functionality that obtained the historical record of the routes of a vehicle or driver, drawing polylines on a map according to the coordinates of the vehicle.
- · Responsible for the creation of a desktop application that connected with previously developed web services, allowing efficient record creation and editing.
- · Created and modified web services and performed unit and integration tests on them.
- · In charge of creating Stored Procedures for the database.

 HTML5
 CSS3
 JavaScript
 jQuery
 Bootstrap 3
 AngularJS
 MySQL Workbench
 CakePHP

 PHP
 Angular 2
 Electron
 Postman
 Git

— Semi-Senior Programmer

Company: Soluciones Medianet / OVenezuela / Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

- · In charge of the development of a responsive informative website.
- · Restructured and developed (fullstack) new modules of a web application for an insurance company.
- · Responsible for updating and creating records, tables and scripts for the database.
- · Dictated a 1 week course about how to maintain the developed application.

HTML5 (CSS3) (JavaScript) (jQuery) (Bootstrap 3) (AngularJS) (C#) (SQL Server 2014) (cPanel) (Filezilla) (Git)

PROJECTS

- Shanelle Productions LLC (2022-Ongoing) ©USA (remote) shanelleproductions.com
- · Developed an informative website with a responsive, interactive and multilanguage design.
- · Hosting configuration and website deployment.

React 18) (react-router v6) (Typescript 4) (Bootstrap 5) (Axios) (cPanel) (Filezilla) (Git)

COURSES

- --- React PRO: Take your foundations to the next level // September 2023
- Creating and Using Generics in TypeScript 4 // Pluralsight // June 2022
- Designing React 17 Components // Pluralsight // June 2022
- Styling React Components // Pluralsight // June 2022
- Building React Apps with TypeScript // Pluralsight // June 2022
- S.O.L.I.D principles and Clean Code // Udemy // June 2022
- TypeScript: your complete guide and handbook // Udemy // March 2020
- JavaScript: ECMAScript 6 and all its details // Udemy // February 2020
- MTA 98-375 certification. Application Development Fundamentals // Microsoft // November 2017

OTHER SKILLS

- Linux handling (Ubuntu Server 16.04 and Ubuntu Desktop 16.04)
- Unit Testing
- Mobile-First, Responsive Design

- Cross Browser Testing & Debugging
- Agile Development & Scrum